<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Category personal in G&#xE1;bor Melis&apos; Blog</title>
        <link>http://quotenil.com/personal.html</link>
        <description>Category personal in G&#xE1;bor Melis&apos; Blog</description>
        <generator>xml-emitter</generator>
        <language>en-uk</language>
        <item>
            <title>Dirty 36Cube</title>
            <link>http://quotenil.com/dirty-36cube.html</link>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a short rant on what I consider to be a
good puzzle and why the trick
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/36_cube&quot; &gt;36Cube&lt;/a&gt; pulls is rather
dirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING&lt;/strong&gt;, spoilers ahead.
Got this crafty beast for Christmas and since then I lost many
evenings to juggling permutations of towers over the inverted city
skyline. The game can be solved two ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;by being cleverer than Euler&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;by being streetwise&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to concentrate on option 2 for the obvious reason. It
can be argued that to solve this puzzle one must be an
outside-the-box thinker, examine every opportunity, leave no stone
unturned. No tower, rather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that I wouldn&apos;t even have solved it without the help of my
wife (who has a few more feet on the ground than I do) must make me
an in-the-box thinker. A naive one, too, who believes that the
differences on the insides of towers must be manufacturing
artifacts. Damn you, thnkbx, you have just crossed the line of
having no decency at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <author>G&#xE1;bor Melis &lt;mega@retes.hu&gt;</author>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Ultimate Fallout 2 Ironman Munchkin</title>
            <link>http://quotenil.com/ultimate-fallout-2-ironman-munchkin.html</link>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m cleaning up the accumulated junk and found this
guide that was written eons ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This build is focused on survival. No save/loading, killap&apos;s final
patch, hard combat and game difficulty. As it is not only ironman
but a munchkin too it must be a sniper since HtH is a bit
underpowered.
See &lt;a href=&quot;http://faqs.ign.com/articles/777/777224p1.html&quot; &gt;this&lt;/a&gt; for good
insights into ironman survival. The two most important pieces of
advice it has is: sneak and outdoorsman. Sneak does not work as well
for me as advertised, that is I cannot end combat in all cases if
the critter I shot did not die. Still, Sneak is still incredibly
useful so it&apos;s tagged and raised to 150% in a hurry. Small Guns and
Speech get tagged as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A true munchkin takes Gifted and Small frame. We rely on Sneak to
keep us from being shot at so Fast Shot would not help too much. The
main emphasis is on survival so endurance and agility must be 10.
NPCs cannot be kept alive and are not needed for most of the game,
plus conversation is ruled by Speech thus charisma is 2. Good
minmaxing so far. Luck is 8 and will be 10 after the Zeta scan. This
is important for Sniper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves us with 18 points for Strength, Perception and
Intelligence. Each point in Perception adds 8% to shooting accuracy.
However putting the same point into Intelligence gives 66 skill
points to spend by level 34. Small Guns shall go beyond 200% where
the cost of 1% is 3 skill points (it&apos;s tagged). 66 points is worth
22% to shooting accuracy. Clearly Intelligence seems the better
place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Perception also determines sequence. Contrary to what &lt;a href=&quot;http://faqs.ign.com/articles/777/777224p1.html&quot; &gt;the
link above&lt;/a&gt; says I
find it important that enemies don&apos;t get a double turn. If combat
could be ended dependably it would be less of an issue, alas, it
cannot. This makes Perception pretty important. With the +1
obtainable by surgery 9 is a good number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strength allows you to carry more which is a small convenience at
the beginning. Even with Small Frame one can get away with a
strength as low as 2 especially with Sulik in the beginning and
later the car. The other, main use of strength is to avoid the 20%
shooting accuracy penalty per point under the weapon&apos;s minimum
strength. At high levels you&apos;ll have 6-7 in strength with armor and
surgery. At lower levels the penalty can be (over)compensated for by
pouring skill points into Small Guns (after reading the books of
course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about strength vs perception? Strength is useful in the early
game before Small Guns is high enough. Perception remains useful at
the end due to its accuracy bonus. Intelligence below 6 is out of
question unless you aim for maximum efficiency at level 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is it that we optimize for? Munchkin combat power, of
course. When? Mostly at the end, say at level 34. That&apos;s 33 levels
gained and 11 perks. So without further ado, pure munchkin starting
stats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;S: 2, P: 9, E: 10, C: 2, I: 7, A: 10, L: 8
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed stats with armor, surgeries, shades, zeta scan, combat
implants:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;S: 7, P: 10, E: 10, C: 2, I: 8, A: 10, L: 10
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skill point needs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;93=28+26+39 Sneak (tagged): 45% -&amp;gt; 151%

265=23+26+39+52+65+60 Small Guns (tagged): 55% -&amp;gt; 221%

21 Speech (tagged): 19% -&amp;gt; 76% (+5% expert excrement expeditor, +10% enhancer)

32 Doctor: ~1% -&amp;gt; 55% (+5% VC training, +20% doctor&apos;s bag, +10% enhancer)

0 Outdoorsman: ~23% -&amp;gt; 110% (books, +20% motion sensor)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&apos;s 411 skill points. Required points in intelligence:
499/33levels/2 = 6.22. A few more points can be saved by reading
Guns and Bullets magazines (max 18). Still, there is a point in
improving Small Guns over 220%, take the gauss rifle or pistol for
example which has a 20% bonus on accuracy and try to shoot someone
in the eye in Advanced Power Armor II from 30 hexes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(SmallGuns = 220) + (8 * (Perception = 10)) + (Weapon bonus = 20)
+ (Ammo AC modifier = 30)
- 30 - (AC = 45) - (4 * (N-Hex = 30)) - (Eyes = 60) = 95%
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Toughness(3)
Lifegiver(2)
Bonus rate of fire
Better Criticals
Sniper
Bonus Move(2)
Action Boy(2)
Living Anatomy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This character is hard to play in the early game. Small Guns takes
some time to develop and the -40% penalty for most guns due to the
low strength is a killer until power armor and/or the Red Ryder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the early game less of a struggle Small Guns shall be raised
pretty early, after Sneak reaches 100% and you have read a few Guns
and Bullets from Klamath, the Den, Redding and Modoc. Grab as many
Scout handbooks as you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Useful links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://faqs.ign.com/articles/777/777224p1.html&quot; &gt;http://faqs.ign.com/articles/777/777224p1.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://user.tninet.se/~jyg699a/fallout2.html#combat&quot; &gt;http://user.tninet.se/~jyg699a/fallout2.html#combat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fanmadefallout.com/fo2-items/&quot; &gt;http://www.fanmadefallout.com/fo2-items/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fanmadefallout.com/procrit/&quot; &gt;http://www.fanmadefallout.com/procrit/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.playithardcore.com/pihwiki/index.php?title=Fallout_2&quot; &gt;http://www.playithardcore.com/pihwiki/index.php?title=Fallout_2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <author>G&#xE1;bor Melis &lt;mega@retes.hu&gt;</author>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Important Remainder</title>
            <link>http://quotenil.com/important-remainder.html</link>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;blog-files/guns.jpg&quot; &gt;example&lt;/a&gt; may speak a hundred
words, but sometimes not even that is enough and you want to be
&lt;a href=&quot;blog-files/dangerous-objects.jpg&quot; &gt;very explicit&lt;/a&gt; about the dangers of
hand grenades on board.
Finally, some trash talk carefully designed to intimidate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;blog-files/remainders.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;trash talk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never die without having made the necessary arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All pictures were taken at M&#xE1;laga airport.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <author>G&#xE1;bor Melis &lt;mega@retes.hu&gt;</author>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>First Post</title>
            <link>http://quotenil.com/first-post.html</link>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;After a long time of waiting to write my own blog
software like true hackers with infinite time do (and those
irritated by Wordpress), I bit the bullet and installed
&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20080610092633/http://lumiere.ens.fr/~guerry/blorg.html&quot; &gt;blorg&lt;/a&gt; - a very low
overhead emacs blog engine - on top of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://orgmode.org/&quot; &gt;org-mode&lt;/a&gt; that I happen to use as an
organizer. Blorg basically converts an org mode buffer to html files
so it is completely static: send me &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mega@retes.hu&quot; &gt;email&lt;/a&gt; if
you have comments, I have no desire to maintain a more complex
solution with comment filtering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small fixes had to be made for blorg to be able to deal with
org-mode 5.17a and I only had time to bring it to some basic level
of functionality. That said here is the
&lt;a href=&quot;blog-files/blorg-init.el&quot; &gt;blorg-init.el&lt;/a&gt; file I&apos;m using right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2020-05-03&lt;/strong&gt;: Since then, this blog has been moved to
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/melisgl/mgl-pax&quot; &gt;MGL-PAX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <author>G&#xE1;bor Melis &lt;mega@retes.hu&gt;</author>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>